Society of Washington Artists 058
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Society of Washington Artists Collection
1890-1966
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Society of Washington Artists (Washington, D.C.)
058
2 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Files This series contains the administrative files of the Society of Washington Artists. Items in this series include: correspondence, Constitution and By-laws, meeting minutes, programs, and newspaper clippings. These items are arranged in this series alphabetically. A bound volume of meeting minutes is housed in a separate box. Series 2: Exhibition Catalogues This series contains the Exhibition Catalogues annually published by the Society of Washington Artists. These catalogues showcase the works of art on display at the Society's annual Exhibition. The dates range from 1891-1963 with a few years missing. The items in this series are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
The Society of Washington Artists was founded in 1892 as an organization meant to support the arts and artists in the city of Washington, D.C. The Society put on an annual exhibition of artwork and gave out an award in conjunction with the newspaper The Washington Star. Notable members include: Everett Warner, Frederick Carl Smith, Susan Brown Chase, Garnet Jex, Heinz Warneke, Ruth A. Anderson, William Henry Holmes (President), Elanor Parke Custis, Louis Amateis, and Alexis Many. The Society ceased operations in the late 1960s.
Custodial History
The materials in this collection reflect the administrative duties of the management of the The Society of Washington Artists. Materials include: correspondence, programs, meeting minutes (including one bound volume of minutes), the official Society Seal, and exhibition catalogues. Also included in this collection are photocopies of many of the materials. Some of the copies do not have corresponding original documents in this collection. The location of these originals is unknown.
Custodial History
The collection was originally filed in the Library Vertical File Collection and on the shelf in the Reference Room. Because of the unique nature of the materials and the amount of materials available, it was decided that a collection should be created out of the materials.
Related Materials
Smithsonian Institution Archives of American Art. Society of Washington Artists records, 1897-1967. OCLC Number 1030334477.
Scope and Contents
The materials in this collection reflect the administrative duties of the management of the The Society of Washington Artists. Materials include: correspondence, programs, meeting minutes (including one bound volume of minutes), the official Society Seal, and exhibition catalogues. Also included in this collection are photocopies of many of the materials. Some of the copies do not have corresponding original documents in this collection. The location of these originals is unknown.
Societies and clubs; Organizational Records; Minutes (Records); Arts; Artists
- Series 1: Administrative Files
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the administrative files of the Society of Washington Artists. Items in this series include: correspondence, Constitution and By-laws, meeting minutes, programs, and newspaper clippings. These items are arranged in this series alphabetically. A bound volume of meeting minutes is housed in a separate box.
  - Clippings, 1895-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contests and Awards (1 of 2), 1925-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contests and Awards (2 of 2), 1925-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Art Situation Commission, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Corcoran Gallery (1 of 2), 1921-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Corcoran Gallery (copies) (2 of 2), 1921-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Exhibitions (1 of 3), 1915-1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Exhibitions (copies) (2 of 3), 1915-1929 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibitions (copies) (3 of 3), 1915-1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Exhibitions (1 of 2), 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Exhibitions (copies) (2 of 2), 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Holmes, 1926-1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Libraries, 1920-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Public Relations, 1921-1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Louis Kidder Sparrow, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Programs, 1912-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Membership, 1923-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes (copies), 1917-1931 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Official Seal (Stamp), Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Series 2: Exhibition Catalogues
  This series contains the Exhibition Catalogues annually published by the Society of Washington Artists. These catalogues showcase the works of art on display at the Society's annual Exhibition. The dates range from 1891-1963 with a few years missing. The items in this series are arranged chronologically.
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1900-1902 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Exhibition Catalogue (2 copies), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Exhibition Catalogue (2 copies), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Exhibition Catalogue, 1953-1956, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 67)